If insects suddenly morphed /mɔːf 变种 变体/
into large beings,
and decided to wage /weɪdʒ 薪水 开展/ war on us,
there's no doubt /daʊt/ that humans
would lose.
We'd simply be crushed /krʌʃ 击垮 迷恋/
by their sheer /ʃɪə 绝对的 十足的/ numbers.
There are an estimated 10 quintillion /kwin'tiljən  10^18  10^20/
individual insects on Earth.
That's a one followed by 19 zeroes.
So, compared with our population
of about 7 billion,
these invertebrates /ɪnˈvɜːtɪbrɪt 无脊椎动物,无骨气的人/ outnumber /ˌaʊtˈnʌmbə  数目超过/
us by more than a billion to one.
Their astounding /əˈstaʊnd 使震惊/ numbers exist
at the species level, as well.
There are more than 60,000
vertebrate /ˈvɜːtɪˌbreɪt 脊椎动物/ species on the planet.
But the class of insects contains
a million known species,
and many others
that haven't been classified.
In fact, these critters /ˈkrɪtə  生物；人；动物/ make up
approximately 75% of all animals on Earth.
So, what's their secret to success?
Insect abundance /əˈbʌndəns 大量/ comes down
to many things
that together make them some of the most
adaptable /əˈdæptəbəl 适应/ and resilient /rɪˈzɪlɪənt 有弹力的；恢复快的；适应力强的/ creatures,
beginning with their impressive
ability to breed.
Many species can produce hundreds
of offspring /ˈɒfˌsprɪŋ 后代/ within their lifetimes.
Most offspring will die,
but more than enough will survive
into adulthood /ˈædʌltˌhʊd/ to reproduce.
Offspring also mature /məˈtjʊə 变成熟/ very rapidly,
so the cycle of reproduction
resumes quickly,
and can occur over and over again
in a short time.
These numbers mean that as a class,
insects harbor /hɑ:bə 港湾 庇护，收养/ a tremendous /trɪˈmɛndəs 极大的，巨大的；极好的；极度的/ amount
of genetic /dʒɪˈnɛtɪk 基因的/ diversity.
The different species contain
a wealth of genetic data
that give them the necessary adaptations /ˌædəpˈteɪʃən/
they need to thrive /θraɪv 繁荣/
in a range of environments
across the planet.
Even some of the most extreme
environments are in bounds /baʊnd 范围/;
Flat bark beetles /ˈbiːtəl 甲壳虫/ can live at
-40 degrees Fahrenheit /ˈfærənˌhaɪt 华氏du/,
Sahara /səˈhɑːrə/ Desert /ˈdɛzət/ ants /ænt/ can venture /ˈvɛntʃə 冒险/ out
when surface temperatures exceed
155 degrees,
and some bumblebees /ˈbʌmbəlˌbiː 大黄蜂/ can survive
18,000 feet above sea level.
Insect exoskeletons /eksəu'skelitn 外骨骼/ also work
like body armor,
protecting insects against
the outside world
and helping them cope with habitats /ˈhæbɪˌtæt 栖息地/
that other creatures can't.
Even their small size,
which we might see as a disadvantage,
is something they use to their benefit.
Because most species are so tiny,
millions of insects can inhabit /ɪnˈhæbɪt 栖息/
a small space
and make use of all the available
resources within it.
This means they can occupy hundreds
of different niches /niːʃ 小群体/ across ecosystems.
Some insects survive by eating the roots,
stems /stɛm 茎/,
leaves,
seeds,
pollen /ˈpɒlən 花粉/,
and nectar /ˈnɛktə 花蜜/ of specific plants.
Others, like wasps /wɒsp 胡蜂/,
make use of live insects
by paralyzing /ˈpærəlaɪz 使瘫痪，使麻痹/ the victims
and laying their eggs inside
so that when the hatchlings emerge,
they can eat their way out
and get nourishment /ˈnʌrɪʃmənt 食物；营养（品）/.
Mosquitos /mɒˈskiːtəʊ  蚊子/ and biting flies feed on blood,
taking advantage of this unusual resource
to ensure their survival.
And a whole bunch of other insects
have built a niche /nɪtʃ 凹陷/ around feces /ˈfiːsiːz 排泄物，渣滓/.
Flies lay their eggs there,
and some beetles /ˈbiːtəl/ even build
large balls out of animal dung /dʌŋ 粪便/,
which they eat and use as accommodation /əˌkɒməˈdeɪʃən 膳宿/
for their eggs.
And then there's the insects' mighty power
of metamorphosis /ˌmɛtəˈmɔːfəsɪs 变态 【动物学】/.
This trait /treɪt 特征/ not only transforms insects,
but also helps them maximize /ˈmæksɪˌmaɪz/
the available resources in an ecosystem.
Take butterflies.
In their larval /ˈlɑːvəl 幼虫/ caterpillar /ˈkætəˌpɪlə 毛虫 履带/ form,
they chomp /tʃɒmp 用力咀嚼/ hungrily through leaves
at a rapid rate
to help them grow and spin cocoons /kəˈku:n 茧/.
But when they emerge as butterflies,
these insects feed only on flower nectar /ˈnɛktə/.
Metamorphosis /ˌmɛtəˈmɔːfəsɪs 变态 【动物学】/ means the larvae /ˈlɑːviː 幼虫复数/
and adults of one species
will never compete /kəmˈpiːt 竞争/ for the same resource,
so they successfully share
an ecological niche /niːʃ 小群体/
without limiting their own success.
This process is so efficient
that an incredible 86% of insect species
undergo complete metamorphosis /ˌmɛtəˈmɔːfəsɪs 变态/.
We're big and they're small,
so it's easy to forget that these critters /ˈkrɪtə  生物；人；动物/
are moving in their millions
all around us,
all the time.
But examine almost any patch /pætʃ 小片 补丁/ of ground,
and you're sure to find them there.
Their numbers are immense,
and their success is unmatched /无可比拟的/.
We may have to accept
that it's insects,
not us,
that are the true conquerors  /ˈkɒŋkərə 征服者/
of the planet.